

WIKOFF.SARA@GMAIL.COM



417.321.3368



2476 S 1675 RD RICH HILL, MO 64779

SKILLS

- Research & Statistics Experience (SPSS)
- Strong Organization and Time Management Skills
- Grant Writing
- Trained Webmaster and Computer expertise (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Canva)
- Program Implementation
- Customer Service
- Funding Development
- Public Speaking/Presentations

EDUCATION

MASTER'S DEGREE

Master's in Public Health Graduated May 2017 Missouri State University 3.6 GPA

BACHELOR'S DEGREE

Bachelors of Science in Health Services Graduated December 2015 Missouri State University 3.39 GPA

PROFILE

My name is Sara Bridgewater and I am an employee of the University of Missouri Extension as a Nutrition and Health Specialist and a County Engagement Specialist. I am currently a Ph.D. student in the Learning, Teaching, and Curriculum Program. I will be doing an emphasis in Online Education. This Ph.D. will allow me to reach my overall career goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nutrition & Health Specialist and County Engagement Specialist at University of Missouri Extension

May 2018 to Current

Provide nutrition and health evidence-based programming to three counties in Missouri, Bates, Cedar, and Vernon. Prepare articles, flyers, help update and create curriculums of nutrition and health information. As the County Engagement Specialist oversees two county offices, help facilitate meetings with extension councils, prepare minutes and agendas for meetings.

Quality Improvement Specialist & PHAB Coordinator at Clay County Public Health Center (CCPHC)

June 2017 to April 2018

Facilitates, manages, and ensures the effectiveness of CCPHC's Quality Improvement Committee. Coordinates efforts to ensure that performance management and quality improvement (QI) are developed and incorporated into strategic initiatives. Make sure that QI incentives are focused and aligned to improve operational and program efficiencies and effectiveness while providing direction for QI policy development and researches and develops QI training programs that focus on enabling the workforce to achieve improvements with priority health concerns.



WIKOFF.SARA@GMAIL.COM



417.321.3368



2476 S 1675 RD RICH HILL, MO 64779

CERTIFIED TO TEACH

A Matter of Balance: Managing Concerns About Falls

Childcare Workshops

Chronic Disease Self-Management

Chronic Pain Self-Management

Cooking Matters for:

- Childcare Providers
- Parents
- Families
- Kids
- Adults

Diabetes Self-Management

Health Information for Men

Food Preservation

Performance Nutrition

Stay Strong, Stay Healthy Level 1 & 2

Tai Chi for Arthritis

Taking Care of You

Walk with Ease

Workplace Chronic Disease Self-Management

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Intern at Taney County Health Department:

December 2016 to May 2017

Being exposed to all the essential parts of a health department. Representing and attending ongoing coalition and board meetings. Currently conducting a research project involving the prevalence of poor nutrition and obesity by the zip code he or she lives at in Taney County. Data is projected to be used for future grants and assistance with the food desert.

Program Coordinator for Growing the Grower USDA Grant & Graduate Assistant at the Taney County Health Department:

January 2016 to May 2017

Build relationships with farmers, organize workshops and prepare grant reports. Coordinate all the components of the USDA grant including fiscal data. Promote and schedule future workshops for the following calendar year. Review scholarship applicants and decide if he or she will receive a scholarship.

Assistant Manager at the Ronald McDonald House:

September 2014 to April 2017

Work with families under stress caused by medical complications. Maintain safety and cleanliness of the environment. Coordinate volunteers for allotted times. Manage money from donors and services. Utilize problem solving and conflict resolutions amongst guests.

Website Designer/Manager at Hume R-8 School:

August 2011 to May 2017

Maintain website by keeping it updated with the newest and relevant information. Keeping newsletters from teachers, new policies, and school board information updated. Rotating current pictures and slideshows of school activities throughout the year.

Nanny for multiple families:

August 2012 to May 2017

Supervise and facilitate children's activities and accompany them safely within the community. Interact with parents and children. Model expectations and educational lessons for children. Sanitize areas as needed. Prepare balanced meals and snacks for children.



WIKOFF.SARA@GMAIL.COM



417.321.3368



2476 S 1675 RD

RICH HILL, MO 64779

TRAINING

CPR/FIRST AID Certified, August 2021-2023

Missouri Training Institute Supervisory Series, January 2021

CONFERENCES

University of Missouri Extension Youth & Family Conference, Columbia, MO May 2018

Public Health Quality Improvement Conference, Atlanta, GA

PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS

National Extension Association of Family & Consumer Sciences

Missouri Extension Association of Family & Consumer Sciences

University of Missouri Extension Association

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Intern at Farmers Market of the Ozarks:

May 2016 to August 2016

Assisted with the farmers market operations such as setting up before and after the market. Implemented a new shopper program. I and other staff members would personally shop at the market for participants. The pilot was very successful and there are plans to expand the personal shopper program in 2017.

Special Events Intern for the American Diabetes Association:

February 2016 to May 2016

Assisted with events, such as the Red Ball Gala. Worked on donor development for the Red Ball Gala. Attended local health fairs and educated others about diabetes.

GRANT WORK

University of Missouri Extension

AmeriCorps Grant: Wrote and submitted a federal grant in Fall 2020. The grant is to support volunteers 55 and older, in-service project activities including a reading buddy program with youth in the community, 4-H and STEM activities, community gardens, weekend backpack program, summer readiness backpacks, and many more. The grant was awarded and began in April 2021.

Awarded: April 2021

Amount per year: \$75,000

Number of Years: 3

Total potential amount: \$250,000

Walk With Ease Grant: Wrote a grant that provided funds for me to get trained in an evidence-based program.

Awarded: June 2019

Amount of grant: \$500



WIKOFF.SARA@GMAIL.COM



417.321.3368



2476 S 1675 RD

RICH HILL, MO 64779

FUNDRAISING

Bates County Extension Annual Summer Chicken Dinner (2018 & 2019)

Bates County Extension Council TRIVIA Night, Silent Auction, and Dinner (2019 & 2020)

COMMITTEES & BOARDS

Bates County Extension Council

Bates County Youth Advocacy Council

Cedar County CHART

Hume School Staff Wellness Committee

Mental Health Committee

Rides to Health and Wealth Network

Vernon County Extension Council

AWARDS

2015 Recipient of the Dr. Don Aripoli Award for Impactful

GRANT WORK CONTINUED

Vernon County Fair Board (2018)

Vernon County Fair Board contracted me to write grants on their behalf to help get a community building built on the fairgrounds. This facility was to benefit the youth and be a place where they could have 4-H and STEM activities.

Grants applied for and received:

Moss Grant (January 2018): \$25,000

FCSF Foundation Grant (August 2018): \$15,000

3M Grant (December 2018): \$20,000

Total amount granted: \$60,000

REFERENCES

Kelly Ast

Community Services Director for West Central Missouri Community Action Agency (417)-667-1448

kast@wcmcaa.org

Melissa Cotton Nutrition and Health Specialist for MU Extension at Jackson County (417)-763-5562

cottonmr@missouri.edu

Wayne Prewitt West Central Regional Director for MU Extension (417)448-7749 PrewittW@Missouri.edu

Lisa Marshall
Taney County Health Department Director at Taney
County
(417) 334-4544
Lisa.Marshall@lpha.mo.gov